<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:sparkle="http://www.andymatuschak.org/xml-namespaces/sparkle"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>Retrace Updates</title>
        <description>App updates for Retrace</description>
        <link>https://retrace.to</link>
        <language>en</language>

        <!-- Latest version should be first -->
        <item>
            <title>Version 0.7.5</title>
            <sparkle:version>7</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>0.7.5</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 20:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<h2>Retrace v<VERSION></h2>
<p>This release focuses on reliability, privacy controls, and major timeline upgrades.</p>

<h3>New in Timeline</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Segment comments with attachments:</strong> Add long-form markdown comments to timeline blocks, attach files, and view full comment threads directly in timeline.</li>
  <li><strong>Tag color indicators:</strong> Timeline tape now shows tag colors for faster visual scanning.</li>
  <li><strong>Scroll orientation option:</strong> Choose horizontal (left/right) or vertical (up/down) scrubbing behavior in Settings.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Privacy Improvements</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Frame redaction pipeline:</strong> Add window-title and browser-URL redaction rules in Settings. Matching frames are masked at capture time.</li>
  <li><strong>Redaction transparency:</strong> Timeline now surfaces redaction reasons so it’s clear why a frame is masked.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Power & OCR Controls</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Expanded OCR power settings:</strong> Pause OCR, process only when plugged in, pause OCR in Low Power Mode, tune OCR priority, and filter OCR by app.</li>
  <li><strong>System Monitor updates:</strong> Better visibility into OCR queue and processing behavior.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Capture & Stability</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>More robust URL capture:</strong> Hardened browser URL extraction pipeline with safer subprocess handling, timeouts, and retries.</li>
  <li><strong>Smoother frame transitions:</strong> Improved reliability around active-window changes.</li>
  <li><strong>Reduced UI stalls/encoder aborts:</strong> Main-thread and encoder-path hardening for steadier long-running capture sessions.</li>
  <li><strong>Timed pause controls:</strong> Pause capture for 5/30/60 minutes with auto-resume countdown in menu bar.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Setup & Release Quality</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Onboarding:</strong> Added app URL permission preflight to improve first-run reliability.</li>
  <li><strong>Release guardrails:</strong> Added stricter preflight checks and sleep/wake validation tooling for safer releases.</li>
  <li><strong>Test suite cleanup:</strong> Internal test reliability improvements.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <enclosure
                url="https://cdn.retrace.to/Retrace-v0.7.5.dmg"
                sparkle:edSignature="nSST4wxVxCFukEFNkjwtieJT+LscWujCPsORBw4a9a5mogLS8R+tJwb9zB9uABaVnjMTJL+qcTdKPp9rJI/xAw=="
                length="9501067"
                type="application/octet-stream"/>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Version 0.7.0</title>
            <sparkle:version>6</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>0.7.0</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2026 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<h2>What's New in v0.7.0</h2>

<h3>What's New</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Smart Processing Levels</strong> — Replaced the manual OCR FPS slider with an intuitive Processing Level system (Low / Medium / High) for simpler performance tuning</li>
  <li><strong>Natural Language Jump-To</strong> — The "Jump to" dialog now understands natural language dates like "yesterday morning" or "last Tuesday"</li>
  <li><strong>Unified Search Routing</strong> — Deep links and search queries now route seamlessly through a single, consistent path</li>
</ul>

<h3>Improvements</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Faster Timeline</strong> — Major main-thread performance improvements for smoother scrolling, rendering, and navigation</li>
  <li><strong>Revamped Filters</strong> — Redesigned date and filter popovers with inclusive date filtering so results include your full selected range</li>
  <li><strong>Dashboard Polish</strong> — Cleaner dashboard layout with improved storage usage visuals and removed distracting persistent alerts</li>
  <li><strong>Redesigned Monitor Tooltips</strong> — System monitor indicators now show richer, better-formatted status information</li>
  <li><strong>Better Feedback Diagnostics</strong> — Feedback submissions now include detailed system diagnostics to help us resolve issues faster</li>
  <li><strong>High-Resolution Display Support</strong> — Improved downscaling for Retina and high-DPI monitors to reduce resource usage</li>
</ul>

<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Fixed timeline flickering caused by double-rerender cycles</li>
  <li>Fixed deep link navigation not jumping to the correct timestamp</li>
  <li>Fixed refresh introducing large time gaps in the timeline</li>
  <li>Fixed thread safety issues in timeline data access</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <enclosure
                url="https://cdn.retrace.to/Retrace-v0.7.0.dmg"
                sparkle:edSignature="fjM3aORaDpPk/d1fL3Xz40b/pDF0BrHhEJF9rR5Mt+Jc2yeK4N0Q8B+TkqkpDzjMnKi87HLeX9te1hUo2HU3Bg=="
                length="8680648"
                type="application/octet-stream"/>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Version 0.6.0</title>
            <sparkle:version>5</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>0.6.0</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 18:34:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<h2>What's New in v0.6.0</h2>

<h3>Live View & Timeline</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Instant OCR on live view — hover and copy any text on your screen in real time</li>
  <li>True smooth scrolling on the timeline, no more frame-by-frame jumps</li>
  <li>Mouse drag scrubbing — click and drag to scrub through your history</li>
  <li>Shift+drag support on live view</li>
  <li>Video playback controls with play/pause</li>
  <li>Fixed multi-display scaling issues</li>
  <li>Escape and search result clicks now clear active filters automatically</li>
</ul>

<h3>Search</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Advanced metadata filters — filter by window title and browser now</li>
  <li>Cmd+K spotlight search in Settings</li>
  <li>Cleaned up and streamlined the entire search UI</li>
  <li>Fixed remaining search result highlighting problems</li>
</ul>

<h3>Performance</h3>
<ul>
  <li>3-5x reduction in energy usage with tile-based OCR change detection and caching</li>
  <li>Power-aware OCR — throttles on battery, ramps up when plugged in (configurable in settings)</li>
  <li>Fixed UI freezes from background task pile-up</li>
  <li>Storage health monitoring</li>
  <li>New OCR system monitor dashboard for real-time processing stats</li>
</ul>

<h3>Keyboard Shortcuts</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Fixed complex multi-modifier shortcuts not registering</li>
  <li>Consistent shortcut behavior across the app</li>
  <li>Added more shortcuts for common actions</li>
</ul>

<h3>Quality of Life</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Permission monitoring for screen recording and accessibility</li>
  <li>Playhead undo functionality (Press cmd z to go back to timestamp)</li>
  <li>Configurable pause recording reminder</li>
  <li>App exclusion list in privacy settings</li>
  <li>Fixed app relaunch ghost instance issue</li>
  <li>Polished drag interactions and share menu reliability</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <enclosure
                url="https://cdn.retrace.to/Retrace-v0.6.0.dmg"
                sparkle:edSignature="qdlOPt/PUlX9/kEMHTfi9pJwL1nBmx/6OvUBP0yH75J83ThN1xYgYQhbstyYpFtZ9/V9FVi6wi0ajmAHRhU2Dg=="
                length="8208806"
                type="application/octet-stream"/>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Version 0.5.1</title>
            <sparkle:version>4</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>0.5.1</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<h2>Bug Fixes & Improvements</h2>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Memory leak fix:</strong> Fixed a memory leak issue</li>
  <li><strong>Storage protection:</strong> Recording now automatically stops if your storage drive becomes disconnected, preventing data loss</li>
  <li><strong>Keyboard shortcuts:</strong> Fixed an issue where shortcuts wouldn't register; you can now also clear shortcuts by pressing Delete or clicking the × button</li>
  <li><strong>Search navigation:</strong> Pressing Escape after viewing a search result now returns you to your search results instead of closing the overlay</li>
  <li><strong>Natural language search:</strong> Time queries like "827am" now work the same as "8:27am"</li>
  <li><strong>UI polish:</strong> Fixed spacing in the feedback form</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <enclosure
                url="https://cdn.retrace.to/Retrace-v0.5.1.dmg"
                sparkle:edSignature="IZqd/Vbr/5+ewDMvT6Snr/rj7+acntUl59+vlLcFx5hA+kYWDFPXMl9g4KNAzh2hmql0ALj7h+NvluiKGH/tBw=="
                length="9412751"
                type="application/octet-stream"/>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Version 0.5.0</title>
            <sparkle:version>2</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>0.5.0</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2026 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<h2>Retrace 0.5.0</h2>

<h3>Highlights</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Major Timeline upgrade: faster scrubbing/scrolling, seamless open/close, improved readability, "show context" in filtered mode, and tighter macOS-native feel.</li>
  <li>Much better Search: Unicode-aware full-text search (better accuracy for non-ASCII text) and improved search UX with grouped/expanded results.</li>
  <li>Tags + filtering: tag your history and filter the timeline by app, URL, title, and tags.</li>
  <li>New Dashboard: redesigned analytics with charts/breakdowns (including better browser breakdowns with favicon support) and daily metrics.</li>
</ul>

<h3>New</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Custom database location and custom storage location support.</li>
  <li>Recording shortcuts + improved settings experience.</li>
  <li>Local-only analytics logging for internal usage/debug (no cloud dependency).</li>
  <li>Milestone/achievement notifications and reminders for required permissions.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Performance</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Faster timeline block calculations and improved timeline responsiveness.</li>
  <li>OCR pipeline improvements: faster realtime OCR for recent frames.</li>
  <li>Video improvements: better compression, fixed B-frame issues, and updated seeking.</li>
  <li>Reduced flicker when switching videos on the timeline.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Rewind importer/querying fixes and improved reliability.</li>
  <li>Better browser URL/title extraction (more browsers supported).</li>
  <li>Segment persistence improvements across Mac sleep/wake.</li>
  <li>Keyboard shortcut fixes and better text selection/copy behavior.</li>
  <li>UI polish: unified colors, improved settings, and updated highlight styling.</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Note: This update includes database migrations. First launch may take a bit longer.</em></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure
                url="https://cdn.retrace.to/Retrace-v0.5.dmg"
                sparkle:edSignature="7RcEKwHs2O8fiXLYdjastOe2WNDJrGjkH+jObPGokCGkMqDLSMOKq9e5Op3OtqECrtRlfwUWh4DdoYJseXsoCA=="
                length="9392680"
                type="application/octet-stream"/>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Version 0.1</title>
            <sparkle:version>1</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>0.1</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2026 01:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure
                url="https://cdn.retrace.to/Retrace-v0.1.dmg"
                sparkle:edSignature="+kUaX5XWd7YDxubVz7T1kUNxwTcv51nt1m6+0N0E1n3yLrmKQhWZJcvHbb41l7CPe/f6aIg1lsu8dKPgsRHXDQ=="
                length="7443561"
                type="application/octet-stream"/>
        </item>

    </channel>
</rss>
